(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T22:26:51.389981",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
What Goes Around
What goes around
comes back around.
“Sit down and listen.”
Back in business to even up the score;
We lost the battle, but now we win the war.
Ah~ This world of dull routines, Living in monotony.
Can't escape it? Watch us, we'll break it.
The old rules do not apply (apply)
You better kiss them all goodbye (goodbye)
It's our turn, so stand aside;
Ain't nothing gonna stem this rising tide.
We're through with convention and being controlled,
We dish out revenge and we're serving it cold.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't you know what we been told?
That “what goes around will come back around,”
They tried to bury us, but we never stay down.
No more playing nice, Now it's just an eye for an eye;
two wrongs are making it right.
We broke our chains, and now,
the world above is gonna come down.
So come and get it!
We're coming around.
We're taking you down.
Shattered glass and tattered walls,
We're coming fast, gonna break it all.
Do you hear the sirens cry? What a perfect lullaby,
'Cause we're taking over tonight.
Yeah.
Hey, hey! Wake up! (Wake up!)
Them's the breaks, you gotta reap what you sow, so it's time to pay!
All your games are uninspired,
We're here to light up a fire.
No more mandates, we can set the world ablaze.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't you know what people say?
That “what goes around will come back around,”
They tried to bury us, but we never stay down.
No more playing nice, Now it's just an eye for an eye;
two wrongs are making it right.
We broke our chains, and now,
the world above is gonna come down so loud,
What goes around is coming back 'round and 'round,
The world is never living this down,
So come and get it!
We're coming around.
We're taking you down.
[Oh, when we come around...]
We won't run, and we won't stop.
We're still not done coming out on top.
[What comes around]
No more silence, no more fear,
Now the world will know we're here,
We'll make it abundantly clear:
What goes around
comes back around.
“BREAKOUT!!!!!”
Feel the rumble underground,
I'm the terror in your walls,
Lashing out until you crumble!
Smoke and fire raining down,
Let the sky fall!
I'll eviscerate your darkened halls;
Till nothing's left of you at all!
With a cry of wrath, I will crush these chains
Until only your wreckage and ash remains.
A rebellious spark lights a blazing flame.
Let it rage, I come uncaged,
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away!
“LET ME OUT!”
“LET ME OUT! LET ME OUT!”
Melt away your grip of steel,
See the binding wearing thin, I will shatter your obsession
There is nothing left to feel;
No delusions.
From the hall of nightmares I ascend,
And I will bring about your end!
With a desperate cry, I will shatter fate
You can sound the alarms, but it's just too late.
See the world reborn in a sea of flame.
Let it dance, my only chance;
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
Take back your maze of lies,
I've seen the other side,
The point of no return,
This fire's gotta burn!
Woah~
"Rise up and break out!"
With a cry of wrath, I will crush these chains, until
only your wreckage and ash remains.
A rebellious spark lights a blazing flame.
Let it rage, I come uncaged,
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
"BREAKOUT!!!!!"
Ah... That was crazy!
Biboo is done, Biboo is tired...
Foot massage! Free foot massage!
Haaaaah~
Is she okay? Look at that!
Hiya, fans!
Hello!
Yay!
自己紹介！ Let's do introductions!
Introductions! Let's do introductions!
Okay!
Shiori Novella here, at your service! Hololive's archiver! And today, I'm with all of Advent together!
Yay!
Woo! Next up, let's go!
Okay! I'm pumped! I'm pumped! I'm pumped! All right!
こんビジュー！ I'm Koseki Bijou, sparkling jewel of Hololive English -Advent-!
Konbijou! I'm Koseki Bijou, sparkling jewel of Hololive English -Advent-!
キラキラーン！ Close up, please!
Sparkling! Close up, please!
Yay!
Okay. Anyway, who's next? Who's next?
Hiya, darlings! This is Hololive English -Advent-'s devilish diva, the one, the only Nerissa Ravencroft, happy to be here with my girls today!
Yay!
And next up is...
I know that you know, I'm Fuwawa!
I know who I am, I'm Mococo!
Together, we're FUWAMOCO! Bau bau!
Ah, extra deep.
Sorry, I got confused.
Together, we're -Advent-! Yay!
Today's a very special day! Yes, it is!
'Cause we're celebrating our 3rd anniversary!
And we're the 3rd gen, our 3rd year!
Extra special!
Yeah! And look around us, the stage! Yeah!
Look at the fire, the balloons, the lights!
It's very Advent-esque!
Yeah, it's so edgy! It is!
Oh, there's a bunch of cracks on the ground because I tripped everywhere and made full cracks!
It attaches to her!
No fighting! No fighting!
I would be laughing...
Well, we have some very special things planned, especially a surprise at the end today, so please stick around, okay?
Yay! A surprise!
So we can go into our next songs, maybe? Let's do it!
Okay!
Bye-bye! Yippee!
Hello, hello...
カミイロアワセ
[Song: Kamiiroawase]
動き出す 体の奥には
Deep inside my stirring body,
生まれたてのネジが騒ぐ ほら
look, the newborn gears are clamoring.
味気ない
Tasteless,
つまらない
boring,
世界の端
at the edge of the world,
見下ろす
looking down,
あなたは誰
who are you?
目の前 眩まれていくの 触れられない未来
Before my eyes, the untouchable future blurs away.
昨日だった世界は 予定調和ばかりだけど
Though the world that was yesterday was full of pre-established harmony,
まだ 絶望 希望 すれすれ紙一重
despair and hope are still a hair's breadth apart.
それも愛しいんだ
Even that is precious,
見えないとしても
even if I cannot see it.
暗がり そっと
In the darkness, gently,
君の手を引いて
taking you by the hand...
走り出す 呼吸に紛れて
Mingled with my running breath,
剥がれ落ちていく 視界は
the field of vision peeling away
間違い探しみたいだね
feels like a spot-the-difference game.
本物はどれか答えて ほら
Tell me which one is real, come on.
暖かい
Warm,
柔らかい
soft,
世界の果て
at the end of the world,
差し出す
reaching out,
あなたは誰
who are you?
飛び交う雑音が 今 心ごとぼやかして
The flying crossfire of noise now blurs my whole heart.
明日にはきっと コントロール不能だけど
Though tomorrow will surely be out of control,
絶望？ 希望？ 君？ 僕？ 裏？ 表？
Despair? Hope? You? Me? Back? Front?
不確かさ歌って その意味を探すよ
I'll sing of uncertainty and search for its meaning.
神様 ちょっと
God, please,
僕の手を引いて
take me by the hand.
生まれた価値を 与えられなくとも
Even if I'm not granted a reason for being born,
重ねた 混沌と日々は 答えをくれる
the chaos and days piled up will give us an answer.
目の前 眩まれていくの 触れられない未来
Before our eyes, the untouchable future blurs away.
昨日だった世界は 予定調和ばかりだけど
Though the world that was yesterday was full of pre-established harmony,
まだ 絶望 希望 すれすれ紙一重
despair and hope are still a hair's breadth apart.
それも愛しいんだ
Even that is precious,
君が選ぶなら
if you choose it.
暗がり ぎゅっと
In the darkness, tightly,
君の手を引いて
taking you by the hand...
リンリンリン おはよう wake up
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up!
リンリンリン おはよう wake up ドキドキモーニング
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up! Doki Doki Morning!
ぱっつん ぱっつん 前髪ぱっつん cutie style
Bangs trimmed straight and cute, cutie style!
やっぱ一直線なら一等賞よ チョーすごい！
Straight across is definitely first place, super cool!
今日のリップ あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's lipstick: that one? This one? Over there? Which one?
which？ チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今 何時？
Which? Wait a sec, check the watch, what time is it now?
集合 集合 放課後 集合 party time
Gather 'round, after school meetup, party time!
だって女子会 参加でガールズトークよ チョーヤバい！
Join the girls' hangout for girl talk, it's so wild!
今日のVIP あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's VIP: that one? This one? Over there? Which one?
which？ チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今 何時？
Which? Wait a sec, check the watch, what time is it now?
知らないフリは キライ！ キライ！
I hate pretending not to know! Hate it!
知らないセカイ 見たい！ 見たい！
I want to see an unknown world! Want to see it!
4次元 5次元 期待！ 期待！
4th dimension, 5th dimension, anticipating it!
10% 背伸びしたい！ したい！
Want to stretch 10% higher! Want to!
っよね！？
Right?!
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよう wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Pleeeease! Wait a sec! Just a sec!
Ring ring ring！ あせらず hurry up
Ring, ring, ring! Don't panic, hurry up!
バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Hectic morning!
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ あわてず make up
Ring, ring, ring! Keep calm, put on makeup!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Pleeeease! Wait a sec! Just a sec!
Ring ring ring！ todayは version up
Ring, ring, ring! Upgrading today!
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-pounding morning!
すっぴん すっぴん メガネが ヘアピン funny face
Barefaced, barefaced, glasses as a hairpin, funny face!
but 3秒 待ってね そっこー変身 チョーはやい！
But wait 3 seconds, instant transformation, super fast!
今日のラップ あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's rap: that one? This one? Over there? Which one?
which？ チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今 何時？
Which? Wait a sec, check the watch, what time is it now?
知らないフリは キライ！ キライ！
I hate pretending not to know! Hate it!
知らないセカイ 見たい！ 見たい！
I want to see an unknown world! Want to see it!
4次元 5次元 期待！ 期待！
4th dimension, 5th dimension, anticipating it!
10% 背伸びしたい！ したい！
Want to stretch 10% higher! Want to!
っよね！？
Right?!
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよう wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Pleeeease! Wait a sec! Just a sec!
Ring ring ring！ あせらず hurry up
Ring, ring, ring! Don't panic, hurry up!
バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Hectic morning!
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ あわてず make up
Ring, ring, ring! Keep calm, put on makeup!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Pleeeease! Wait a sec! Just a sec!
Ring ring ring！ todayは version up
Ring, ring, ring! Upgrading today!
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-pounding morning!
リンッ リンッ リンッ おはよう wake up
Ring, ring, ring, good morning, wake up...
お・ね・が・い チョ待って チョ待って
Pleeeease, wait a sec, just a sec...
Ring ring ring あせらず hurry up
Ring, ring, ring, don't panic, hurry up!
バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Hectic morning!
リンッ リンッ リンッ あわてず make up
Ring, ring, ring, keep calm, put on makeup!
お・ね・が・い チョ待って チョ待って
Pleeeease, wait a sec, just a sec!
Ring ring ring todayは version up
Ring, ring, ring, upgrading today!
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-pounding morning!
リンッ リンッ リンッ おはよう wake up
Ring, ring, ring, good morning, wake up!
Ring ring ring おはよう wake up
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-pounding morning!
Bad Apple!! feat. nomico
[Song: Bad Apple!! feat. nomico]
流れてく 時の中ででも
Even within the flowing of time,
気だるさが ほらグルグル廻って
this sluggish feeling keeps spinning around.
私から 離れる心も
Even the heart that drifts away from me,
見えないわ そう知らない？
I cannot see it... Don't you know?
自分から 動くこともなく
Without even making a move on my own,
時の隙間に 流され続けて
I just keep drifting through the cracks of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't care about anything around me;
私は私 それだけ
I am simply me, and that's all.
夢見てる？ 何も見てない？
Am I dreaming? Am I seeing nothing at all?
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉？
Are my own words pointless to even speak?
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Feeling sad is just exhausting;
何も感じず...
it's better to feel nothing at all...
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if given bewildering words,
自分の心 ただ上の空
my heart is just up in the clouds.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
if I change everything, I'll turn it black.
こんな自分に 未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に 私はいるの？
Do I truly belong in a world like this?
今切ないの？ 今悲しいの？
Am I hurting now? Am I sad now?
自分の事も わからないまま
Without even understanding myself,
歩むことさえ 疲れるだけよ
even walking forward is just exhausting.
人のことなど 知りもしないわ
I don't know or care about anyone else.
こんな私も 変われるのなら
If someone like me could change,
もし変われるのなら 白になる
if I can change, I'll turn white.
流れてく 時の中ででも
Even drifting in the midst of time,
気だるさが ほらグルグル廻って
look, listlessness just spins round and round.
私から 離れる心も
Even my heart drifting away from me,
見えないわ そう知らない
I can't see it; yeah, I just don't know.
自分から 動くこともなく
Without making a move myself,
時の隙間に 流され続けて
constantly swept away in the cracks of time,
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't care about anything around me.
私は私 それだけ
I am just me, and that is all.
夢見てる？ 何も見えてない？
Am I dreaming? Am I seeing nothing?
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉
My own words are useless to even speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Grieving is nothing but exhausting,
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
so it's better to live feeling nothing at all.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if given perplexing words,
自分の心 ただ上の空
my heart is completely spaced out.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
if I change everything, I'll turn it black.
動くのならば 動くのならば
If I make a move, if I make a move,
すべて壊すわ すべて壊すわ
I'll destroy everything, I'll destroy it all.
悲しむならば 悲しむならば
If I am to grieve, if I am to grieve,
私の心 白く変われる？
can my heart change into white?
貴方の事も 私のことも
About you, about myself,
全ての事も まだ知らないの
about everything—I still know nothing.
重い目蓋を 開けたのならば
If I open my heavy eyelids,
すべて壊すのなら 黒になれ！
if everything is to be destroyed, turn to black!
Yeah! Woohoo!
Bau bau! Bau bau! Yeah!
Doki doki m... Doki doki money! Beanz!
Yeah! Oh! Ah! Ayy!
What the heck?! Nothing! Hi!
Hold down.
Hi! You two performed such a special song together too!
Yeah! We performed Kami-iro Awase...
Kami-iro Awase.
...which is from Danganronpa. And I actually love this song, so I picked it. I'm sorry.
It's okay! It's okay!
But I've always wanted to sing it with you, 'cause it's one of my favorite songs. But it gives me really, really bad luck every time I listen to it.
What the... I'm the bad luck doll!
Really bad things happen to me, so I thought maybe if I sing it with Shiori then it'll fix my luck!
That's not how it works!
Lucky! Or unlucky. Oh boy...
Uh, and we also, all sung Bad Apple together, right?!
Uh, and we also all sang Bad Apple together, right?!
You can play Bad Apple on anything, including Advent 3D!
And Bad Apple's actually been a song we wanted to do together all the way since before we broke out of the cell, right?
Yeah! We finally got to do it!
And not just, you know, just the five of us, but it was extra special with all the shadows behind us!
Did you see? It was kind of like the original MV, right?
Yeah, it was so cool! Love that! Memories!
Aw, shadows!
All right. Whew! Wow! Maybe that's not just the end of everything!
There's more?
Oh yes! Up next, we have something special!
Ooh! What is this special thing?
Special surprise!
Biboo split! Yeah! Look at that!
I'm sinking! I'm sinking! Hurry!
Hurry! Please hurry! I'm sinking! Wait...
No! Bye!
シオシオ
ShioShio
リサリサ
RisaRisa
魔界乃番犬シスターズ☆★
Sisters☆★
この世界に爆誕“BAU”DOLです
Born into this world, we are "BAU"DOLs!
BAUBAU!!
BAU BAU!!
シオリ (Shiori!!)
Shiori (Shiori!!)
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa (Nerissa!!)
Shio+RissaはShiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
Shio + Rissa is Shiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
シオリ (Shiori!!)
Shiori (Shiori!!)
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa (Nerissa!!)
Shio+RissaはShiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
Shio + Rissa is Shiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
BAUBAU～!!
BAU BAU~!!
Wake upしたら君にMorning
When I wake up, good morning to you
Newな出会い 鼻利かせSearchして
On the scent searching for new encounters
ドキドキDoggy
Heart-pounding Doggy
右に左 BAU BAU BAU
To the right, to the left, BAU BAU BAU
悩んでいても来ちゃうFuture
Even if you're worried, the future will come
まずは目の前の道Stepして
First, take a step on the road before you
Happy Lucky Puppy
一緒に歩こうよ
Let's walk together!
ドーナツの穴の中には
Inside the donut hole
きっと きっと
surely, surely,
夢が詰まってるから
dreams are packed tightly inside!
シオシオ (Wa!!Foo!!)
Shio-Shio (Wa!!Foo!!)
リサリサ (Come on!!)
Rissa-Rissa (Come on!!)
魔界乃番犬シスターズ☆★
Guard Dogs of the Demon Realm Sisters☆★
2匹が揃えば もう大騒ぎ
When the two of us get together, it's total mayhem!
もあもあ (Motto!!)
More, more (Motto!!)
ハロハロ (BAUBAU!!)
Ruff, ruff (BAUBAU!!)
迷わずに Go my way
Without hesitating, go my way
君の絶対味方“BAU”DOLです
We're your absolute allies, the "BAU"DOLs!
この世界に爆誕“BAU”DOLです
Born into this world, we are "BAU"DOLs!
BAUBAU!!
BAU BAU!!
シオリ (Shiori!!)
Shiori (Shiori!!)
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa (Nerissa!!)
Shio+RissaはShiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
Shio + Rissa is Shiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
シオリ (Shiori!!)
Shiori (Shiori!!)
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa (Nerissa!!)
Shio+RissaはShiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
Shio + Rissa is Shiorissa (SHIORISSA!!)
BAUBAU～!!
BAU BAU~!!
ばうばうー！
BAU BAU~!
Moco's here to play
Yeah
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity (Ha-a-a-a)
Biboo
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, BIBOO BIBOO
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, BIBOO BIBOO
Better hit quicksave 'cause
Moco's here to play!
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, BIBOO BIBOO
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCK IN!
Moco Moco
(Hahaha)
Lingering in him
He's made of sin, nothing in the abyss he calls a soul
(Eating at him, there's a rage, He hunts to feel any little thing)
He's desperate, sure - but even more he won't live another day
(Picked the wrong victim and cried “God spare me oh please!”)
(Picked the wrong victim and cried "God spare me oh please!")
As light left his eyes, She contemplates how her heart it aches
The memory of him keeps her warm and safe
In her bed there lies
A pile of bones and echos Of a love that's dead and gone
A pile of bones and echoes Of a love that's dead and gone
(Seen it all, been done before, cliche but it's real...... history-)
(Seen it all, been done before, cliche but it's real... history—)
Repeating Over, over again
You are all the same in the end
Oh you're restricted
(In the bitter end)
You've no conviction
Tell me your story now
Now~!
Lalalala lala~
Set it in stone Let it be known By those who pay attention
Restricted by your own hand, the end
Aaah♡♡♡
Sniff, sniff, sniff
Oh, I know this smell - It belongs to my darling!
Much more of it, and I'll be smothering you in kisses!
Oh, wait my love♡
I can't stop, Fuwawa's almost there~
Think my body might overheat
'Cause when I look at you my heart can't help but skip a beat
Your eyes that shine and dazzle, soft lips that get me frazzled
The lovely way you smile (ooh!)
Past the point of no turning back
Yeah, I've been struck by cupid, all my sense goes
boo-boo-boo-boo-boom!
This overflowing love's so haaaard♡
Feel it coursing through me like a heat that I can't disregard
Hello precious kitten, you can drop the coy disguise
Don't you turn away from me, just look me in the eyes
Forecast is clear skies, BAUBAU sensor's all powered up!
Ope! Hehe
I've found you!
Here I am, bursting at the seams to tell you how I'm feeling
Love you, love you - baby, won't you marry me
You're my one, my only, shining princess~
Yeah, you know I won't let you go!
Wedding bells are ringing and the guests are waiting
God himself can't stop me, yeah I'll make ya mine
We'll have a perfect honeymoon!
You'll be mine, yeah, I'll getchu
Holic♡ for my waifu~
CHU!
Advent Shuffle!
Shuffle Medley! Advent Shuffle Medley!
I wanted to do that so badly for so long!
Wait, it's a surprise! Surprise!
Ooh, at first we started with Shiori's song!
Wah wah wah wah!
BAUBAU! Biboo, that was so cute, the "yeah"!
Yeah, it feels really weird to hear another HoloAdvent singing our song, huh?
Right? Each other's song!
Shiori's and then Nerissa's! Yeah, thank you!
It was so much fun! Double tadaima!
It was so much fun! Double "I'm home"!
And then right after, it was moko moko...
Yeah! Shiori, you rocked it!
You were great! Rocked it! Biboo!
And then after that was Biboo with... March of the Snails!
Marshmallow Snail! So cute!
Oh yeah! Escargot! Escargot!
Did I do it alright, or...? You did!
I love how you start like this, Biboo!
I'm a little teapot!
And then Mococo came in! Yeah! Oyu no mae houhe!
And then Mococo came in! Yeah!
I was so happy because I love your song, Nerissa's song, but I'm angry!
I know! Why? なんで？
I know! Why? Why?
Look at those lyrics!
Eh? You did this on purpose! How dare you call the BAUBAU sensor this?!
Huh? You did this on purpose! How dare you call the BAUBAU sensor this?!
I just translated them from Japanese!
She did it on purpose! I didn't! It's how they originally sound in my song!
You liked it! You liked it!
Ah, BAUBAU!
But it was so much fun being able to combine all of our songs into a medley like that. That's something I've wanted to do for a long- especially because of the Holo Shuffle, those are so fun.
Right? So being able to have an Advent Shuffle... Yeah!
So awesome, but, uh... Well...
I hate to say this, Advent...
What? What? Wait, it's not over, right?
It's not over, that's not it, it's worse. It's not over? It's worse?
We have to test something.
A test? Oh, I didn't study! Guys... It's not math, right?
We need to test our nakama power!
Oh my god! What's happening?
We've done a shuffle. We've done this performance. For three years now, we've been carried through, together as a team. A team!
Do we truly have the 仲間の力?
Do we truly have the power of friends?
Well, how should we test this nakama? With the power of God and anime on my side?
I'll show us the power of teamwork and friendship! Yeah! Let's do it! Power!
Well, uh, look behind us, and what do you see?
Wait, a shadow! Shadows! I'm not going to be scared.
There's some shadows! Whoa, that's a sexy shadow!
Can I do something creative? Okay, okay. Wait, wait, okay, okay.
And then you...
私の、私そんな... Ta!
My... I'm like that... Ta!
Yay! Thank you, thank you! I've always wanted to do that, thank you, thank you so much!
Okay, so... What are we doing? What are we doing?
Uh, I've actually done a collab with Pokey to prepare this.
Whoa! Pokey's in this? Pokey, my precious! Yay!
Um, he is going to be giving us topics, and we are going to have to create...
...uh, with the shadows, with our bodies, whatever the topic given to us is. So...
...uh, we can't rely on our amazing appeal, like usual, we simply have to use only our shadows.
Ooh, nice! Our silhouettes, as you will. So...
Pokey! Are you out there? Are you ready, Pokey? Give us the first prompt!
Oh! Yeah! Yay! Ah, favorite animal!
Okay. Animal, animal. Demon dog, demon dog, right? Demon dog, our favorite animal!
I like cats. I like cats too. Let's make cats.
Cats! Yeah! Okay! I feel like demon dogs looks...
Wait, what?
Yeah.
I love my demon dog.
I like human cat.
Why aren't you Why don't you do a cat, huh?
Yeah.
Umigucat, Umigucat.
Umigucat then. Okay.
How are we going to do this?
We got to do the ears and the whiskers.
Wait, what? I look like an entire ear.
Okay, how should we how should we be a cat?
I'm not tall enough. How do I get up there?
Did they mention for time? Do we have one minute?
Be the cat.
I'm going to be the ear too. We're making the head.
Okay, okay. This is a head. This is the head of a cat's mouth.
I'm going to be the, uh... Oh, should I...
Should I be... Yeah.
I'm not tall enough to be an ear!
You'll be the ear. I'm going to be an ear.
Is this a cat?
Wait, try to make it... No, more ears. There's not enough...
Okay, okay, you're ears.
I'm the mouth. I'm the mouth. I'm the mouth.
Does it look like a cat yet?
It looks more like like a a pumpkin.
It's Meow.
I'm an ear. My hand is an ear.
It's pretty good. It's pretty good.
That's a cat.
Is this a cat? Meow.
I think it's a cat. Meow.
A cat, right? Meow. Meow.
And then there's the tail.
Yeah, we've got the tail going!
Meow.
What is this?
What do we What do you think?
It's a very unique cat.
Double 100%. What do you think?
Adventites, give us 100% score, guys.
Yeah! Come on! What do you think?
It's a cat from the underworld, okay? It's different.
Yeah, that's all it is.
100%. This is how it looks. You're doubting us?
At that time, she knows. It's a cat!
It's a cat, isn't it? Yeah.
We did it!
Let's move on to the next prompt!
[Prompt: Giant Face] Giant Face.
Oh, I got this. I got this.
Okay, eyes, eyes. The eyes like this, right?
Help.
Can you reach? You're too short. Can you reach?
Get close.
Okay, okay. This is an eye. This is an eye.
This is also an eye.
Can somebody else grab her other foot?
Okay, fine. You grab her other one.
Okay, this is the mouth. This is the mouth.
Why do you guys have 4 eyes?
It's a mouth. Okay, the smile.
Smile. This is the eye.
Guys, don't hold her legs.
Go make something else on the face.
We need to make it a wide smile.
It's good.
I'm an ear. I'm an ear.
I'm an eyeball.
No, no, it's starting to look like a mouth.
Shiori and Nerissa, okay, you look good. You look like the eyes.
Biboo, you can be an ear, okay?
Oh, I'm an ear? You're an ear, yeah.
Oh, this is pretty good.
This is so cool.
This is pretty good. This is a pretty good face.
Is that a face, you guys?
It looks pretty good.
Yeah. Wait, hold the pose! Hold the pose!
Nerissa, Nerissa, can you scoot scoot scoot? Yeah!
Yeah! Woo!
Good! That was definitely a Giant Face.
That was a good face. Congrats.
You want help?
There. There you go.
A bye. Good piece.
All right, what's the next one?
Come on, Pokey. Okay, bring it up.
Did you guys hear that?
[Prompt: Advent] Ooh. We have to write Advent.
Oh. Whose letter is...
Okay, one letter at a time! One letter at a time!
Okay, let's start with A. Who wants to make A?
I want to make the A. We got to do this with A first, right?
Okay, taller people make A! Taller people make A!
I'm tall!
You are tall indeed.
Someone needs to be short. Okay, that looks like an A.
Yeah, A! That's an A?
Okay, let's move to the next one.
D, D, D! D?
Oh, this should be easy.
You did You do the top. Okay. Okay.
Wait, are we backwards? Don't we need to...
They can They can flip it.
Wait, is this is this...
It's okay. It's okay. We'll do it willingly.
I need to be held, and then I can be the the the D portion of it.
Is this a D?
I don't know, man. I don't think this is working yet.
Is this a letter?
No, this in no way... Wait, wait, why Why don't we do a small d?
How does a d look again? Just a lowercase d.
Oh, okay, D. Did you come here... Lowercase d, lowercase d.
Lowercase d.
Yeah, that'll be easier. Someone just has to like go like this, right?
Like like this?
Now someone needs to stand up. Mococo, pick up Fuwawa.
We made a ball. Looks like a d.
Is this a d? Is this a d?
Is this good? Is this a d?
What is this? Honestly, it looks like a dead...
D. Pick up Fuwawa.
Make her move, Fuwawa. My tail is in the way!
Why does it look...
Stand up!
Look, that's a d. That's good enough. That's good enough. That is a d. E.
E! Let's make a big E.
Wait, aren't we supposed to do V? Okay.
Mococo, top Fuwawa. Fuwawa.
Be the tall back. Come come here, come here.
What letter are we on? E. E.
Where's the V? Where's the V? V, advent!
This way, this way. V, V, V. V!
V! V!
No, you guys have to You guys have to be on the other side.
Oh, okay. Wait, wait, wait. We could be...
Look at this.
Yeah, yeah. Like this, yeah, yeah.
Yeah!
I'm doing it! / We're doing it!
Okay, now we got E.
Yeah! Yay!
Okay, E. A-D-V...
I'll be the middle. I'll be the middle E.
You will be the tall. The tall, I'll be the tall.
Okay, I'll sit down. Someone needs to be the bottom.
I'll be the bottom.
You got it? Okay.
How about this one? Yeah, yeah, yeah...
Moco-chan, get in the way!
Why are all the arms out like this?
Oof!
Ah! Is this an E?
It's supposed to be an E.
I don't know why Rissa is all the way over there, though.
You have to get up, you have to crouch!
You have to crouch, you have to crouch!
Okay, okay. There, E! E!
It's a very weird E, but it's an E!
No, lower your head a little bit. Lower your head, there we go, E!
Is this better? Yes!
Yay! E!
Is this a backwards E?
Okay, it's fine, don't worry.
All right, N! N!
Okay, okay, N. Two two strong pillars, who are the tallest?
I'm a pillar! Pillar, pillar! Okay.
Okay, okay. Wait, wait...
What's going on here? Yeah, good fun, good fun.
Okay, okay. Sorry, she's been waiting for this all day, guys.
Huh? How is this an N?
It's an N! Yeah, yeah, this is good, this is good.
Go closer.
N! It's an N!
Yay! N!
Okay, a T! T!
Okay, this is Overlap, okay? Overlap, overlap!
Wait, someone have to be the front.
Why are we just in a straight line?
My T is too strong. I'll just be a pillar. I'll be a pillar. I'll just be a pillar.
T! T!
Yeah! Yay! We did it!
Guys! We did it!
We proved our nakama power to the world!
Power of nakama!
And we overcame the shadows.
So... now I think it's time to move on.
Aw... Oh, I kind of like how the shadows went together with us.
Shadows suit us, I think.
We were super cute, right?
Advent! Advent!
We overcame the challenge, so...
Yes! Let's continue!
Yes! Advent!
[Unchained
Lyrics: Steph　Music: TIDY, Kengo Ishibashi
Arrangement: Kengo Ishibashi]
[Unchained
Lyrics: Steph | Music: TIDY, Kengo Ishibashi
Arrangement: Kengo Ishibashi]
I was always looking for a beacon in the dark times;
My guiding light.
All the captive dreams I held so dear,
Waiting for a moment to live without fear.
Ever since I met you, we've been living in the sunshine,
So warm, so bright.
My heart is full, the skies are clear,
The road goes on forever, we made it so far together.
This is our song,
A story forged in bonds.
A journey of the heart
that goes on and on...
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am.
I know I'm not alone, I got a new life
In the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
You believed in me, and that's where it all began
Now hope is everlasting
I can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か遠くから
From far away,
辿り着いた
having arrived,
輝きたたえる
praising the brilliance,
よすがへ降り立つ
landing upon the sanctuary,
We're unchained.
I was shut away, I waited every day,
My whole world was so small (so small)
But here and now, it's like the walls just fall away;
I can see it all.
Out here in the light with you, it's such a perfect view;
Blue skies and sunsets.
The joyful days that seem to fly,
The heartfelt moments and the good times,
And through all these years,
Through tenderness and tears,
I found my way at last,
'Cause I knew you were right here.
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am.
I'm not afraid, 'cause even on a dark night,
I can feel the glow of the starlight.
Now the world I see is as bright as you became.
I will cherish every moment,
this is what it means to live unchained.
Don't cry, you can breathe free;
I'm here if you need me.
Let go of all your heartache,
We made it through, it's the dawning of a new day
Feel the world's embrace,
Oh, what a joyful place
This is where I wanna be, so come with me;
keep dreaming...
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am,
I know I'm not alone, I got a new life
In the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
You believed in me,
and that's where it all began
Now hope is everlasting
I can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か遠くから
From far, far away,
辿り着いた
we arrived at last.
輝きたたえる
Full of radiant light,
よすがへ降り立つ
we descend upon this haven.
We're unchained.
Thank you!
And that was Unchained for the very first time!
Thank you! We're so happy to be able to perform it for you all today!
Um, but not just that, there's other songs from the story of Advent that we performed...
Original songs!
We've got a lot of original songs now, huh?
I know, I think... I think my favorite has to be, uh... "What Goes Around"!
A cutie, too. I like it's sassy.
A cutie, too. I like that it's sassy.
Well, we have so... like Genesis is amazing too.
And... I like, I like Break Out.
I like Break Out! I like Break Out!
I know the choreo!
Break out! Break out!
It's all right, it's all right... Um, yes...
This is a special day! 1st anniversary, all of a sudden!
1st anniversary!
I can't believe it's 1 year already together with you guys and with the Adventurers!
Yes, Advent strong all together!
Advent strong! It went by so fast!
And we'll have many more years!
Thank you so much, Adventurers, for always being here during our silly times, playing this and that game all together...
All the gnomes... Yeah, gnomes! Plinko!
And when we release special original songs and covers too, right?
And we're looking forward to all the new heights...
...that hopefully we'll be able to reach together with you and all five of us too.
Let's keep aiming for the stars!
Bau bau! Yeah! We're gonna grow taller!
Speaking of the next star...
...how about we present our new original song...
...Spotlight!
Yeah! Bau bau!
Get the mics, hit the lights, race ya to the stage!
Check, one, two! Now we're on the way—
Take a deep breath, this is our moment
Yeah, we can make it, we're chasin' after greatness.
Watch the curtain rise, goin' up, goin' up
Feel electrified, never stop, never stop
Mm, we got that vibe, yeah, you know that's right
Gotta keep it hype, it's our time!
No more fear, feel alive
I'm right here, by your side
Cue me in and let the music play.
Take it away!
Come on, steal a little spotlight, spotlight!
I wanna see you shine bright, shine bright!
Now you're ready for the big time, big time!
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight
It hits ya like a bullseye, bullseye!
You gotta chase it for your whole life
Whole life!
So run with all of your might
to the spotlight
Play that rhythm, they won't know what hit 'em!
Gonna be unforgettable,
so much fun, it's criminal
We keep plotting to steal the show, oh yeah
On your mark, and ready, set, GO! GO!
Oh, we never miss
What a bop, what a bop
Yeah, we're lovin' this
Keep it up, keep it up
Take it all in, this is who we are, in the dark
we shine like stars!
No more tears
here we are
Feel those cheers
in your heart
Let the whole world know it's you and me, finally free!
Come on!
Steal a little spotlight
Spotlight!
I wanna see you shine bright
Shine bright!
Now you're ready for the big time
Big time!
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight
Spotlight!
It hits ya like a bullseye
Bullseye!
You gotta chase it for your whole life
Whole life!
So run with all of your might
Steal that spotlight
Aura farming baddies in a getaway car,
Rizz 'em up and never stop, gonna be stars
Breakin' out, breakin' rules, joking like it's April Fool's,
Ooh...
Like a moth to a flame
You been caught, welcome to our game!
It's your move, wanna play?
You're confused, goin' renegade?
Advent, yeah, that's right,
Advent, steal that spotlight!
Life's sweeter on the run, just having fun!
One, two, three, four!
Ooh...
Steal a little spotlight
Spotlight!
I wanna see you shine bright
Shine bright!
Now you're ready for the big time
Big time!
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight
Spotlight!
It hits ya like a bullseye
Bullseye!
You gotta chase it for your whole life
Whole life!
So run with all of your might
to the spotlight
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight,
Steal the spotlight, now we're really rockin'
Steal the spotlight, run with all your might...
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight,
Steal the spotlight, now I think you got it!
Steal the spotlight
BAU BAU! Yeah!
Yeah, that was our new song, Spotlight!
Spotlight! Spotlight!
Did you guys like it?
We really are aura farming baddies in a getaway car! Yeah, that's right!
Ad-vent, steal that spotlight!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, I've heard this... this sounds kind of familiar.
No, it's not! No, it's original! No, that's definitely not it!
It is our original song!
Yeah, yeah, we're innocent!
We are the aura farming baddies in a getaway car!
Yeah!
Please listen to Advent's newest song, Spotlight, lots and lots, okay?
Over and over! Woo!
All right. Well, if we can, since we're getting close to the end, then maybe perhaps we should make some individual announcements?
Announcements! Go ahead! Tell us!
So, I'll start. While we don't have any Advent joint merch,
I believe all of us will probably have anniversary merch, and I am no exception.
I think the highlight item this year is a dakimakura!
What?!
Double-sided with the office lady and my pajama outfit, so please look forward to it!
Office lady by day...
Yes! And then, I've also had a new cover come out recently of a song that we just performed here today,
"Bad Apple!!", in English, so please listen to it!
Yeah! Yay!
And Koseki Bijou!
Oh! Whatcha got?
Look at her pose! She's awake!
Hey everyone! Biboo just released a new VRChat room,
and you might want to check it out 'cause it's pretty cool. Got a little arcade bar thing going on around.
Come on and visit, yeah yeah yeah!
And also, you know, Biboo is a little bit kind of close to like a million subscribers...
Wow! Yay!
So maybe if you could subscribe to my channel, I would be a little, you know, a little happy.
In fact, maybe you should subscribe to all of Advent! Yeah! Subscribe to Advent!
And shoot your hit, too! Yeah! Shoot it!
Eh? Heh, that's me!
Make sure you guys subscribe and like this video!
Like and subscribe!
Hit the button, hit the button! Hit the be— The bell, ring...
The notification button, yeah! Leave a comment, subscribe...
Do what you gotta do! Do what you gotta do! Yeah!
Next up!
Huh? What? That's right! FUWAMOCO!
Yeah!
Recently, we released a brand-new original song, "Mekurumeku Rendezvous"!
It's also the ending theme to an anime! Yeah!
So please go check it out!
We also have a big announcement really soon!
Big announcement!
Please look forward to that, okay? Yeah, okay!
Oppa!
And Shiori! That's me!
For Shiori Novella of hololive Advent, I have a mini visual manga series!
Ooh! Yay!
The first two episodes are already out!
Already out?! Oh my god!
No way! Whoa!
Nani?! Yeah!
What?! Yeah!
But it has Japanese and Korean subtitles, and there'll be more to come, so please tune in when you can!
Get excited! Get excited!
Wow, that's it for today, but...
Aw! I can't believe it's ending!
Advent continues to go forward together, you know that takes strength!
Please continue to cheer us on and let's continue to be steady, okay? Yeah! Let's go!
Okay! It's hug time!
Advent strong together?
Yes, Advent together is strong.
Wait, hug! Hug! Hug! Hug time!
Wait, it's hug time! Group reset!
Advent...
Strong!
Bye-bye!
Okay, now come here, come here, come here! Hug!
Are you okay?!
Bye-bye!